Andrew J. Currie

<u>andrew.j.currie0@gmail.com</u> | 480-201-9948 | Lake Katrine, New York LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewjcurrie0/ | GitHub: https://github.com/curriecoder| Portfolio: <u>https://curriecoder.github.io/react-portfolio/</u>

Summary

Software Engineer/Web Developer and. U.S. Army Veteran with a long-standing passion for technology and programming. Extensive experience working as a technician in the aerospace industry. Recently graduated from the University of Pennsylvania Coding Boot Camp. Equipped with an attention to detail that enables pixel-perfect front-end designs rendered from crude or sophisticated wireframes as well as experience with back-end technologies including MySQL, NoSQL, Mongoose, and Heroku.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, AJAX, SASS

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Webpack

Projects

Chessmate | https://github.com/curriecoder/Chessmate | https://mighty-ravine-90150.herokuapp.com/

Front-end, Back-end, Lead Developer

- An app for chess enthusiasts to practice their craft, and better their game.
- Chessmate allows users to take their chess performance to the next level through challenging puzzles
 and a collection of resources to study. Familiar with all of the technologies used in order to
 troubleshoot bugs in deployment/production environments.
- Tools/Languages: Chessgrounds, LiChess API, React.js, Express, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Heroku

Project Management Application | https://github.com/curriecoder/project-management-application | https://stormy-fortress-72998.herokuapp.com/ | Back-end, Front-end | <a href="https://stormy-fortress-72998.herokuapp.com/

- This application allows users to network and manage projects with definitive timelines.
- Project Management Application accomplishes the goal of getting people together in order to work on a project collectively. The app allows users to create a profile, connect with other users, and plan projects with sub tasks to be completed. Responsibilities in this team were building the database models and seeding the database as well as handling the front-end design within the CSS framework Bulma.
- Tools/Languages: Node.js, Express.js, Sequelize, MySQL, MySQL 2, dotenv, bcrypt, express-session, express-handlebars, connect-session-sequelize, nodemon, materialize, day.js.

Pack Rat | https://github.com/curriecoder/Pack-Rat | https://nazikbestcoder.github.io/Pack-Rat/Lead Design, UX/UI Engineer, Lead Developer

- Pack Rat is an application for the prepared traveler with it's comprehensive list of national parks and packing checklist.
- This project accomplishes preparing users for the weather, terrain, and required packing for any venture into the United States Parks. Responsible for building the wire frame design and pitching the

- application- concept for approval. As the Lead Developer on this project, working with the team to determine individual strengths in order to complete the project by the deadline.
- Tools/Languages: Bulma CSS Framework, OpenWeatherMap, NPS API, NASA API, jQuery, HTML.

Work Experience

Working Solutions Feb 2021 - Current Connection Specialist Remote

- Professionally represent clients of Working Solutions as a remote contractor supporting live customer-consumer relationships.
- Carefully keep all sensitive personal information secure in accordance with applicable federal laws.
- Constantly communicating with resource agents to ensure company SOP is always followed.

Happy Currie Studios

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

Music Producer/Primary Sound Engineer

Ashland, OR

- Accurately interpret customers' requests as appropriate actions within a digital audio workspace.
- Resourcefully located appropriate distribution network for product dispersal adhering to the set budget.
- Smoothly conducted daily operations of prepping musicians as well as recording/producing of all audio files.

Sabbatical Jun 2016 - Nov 2018

- Continued education at Mesa Community college
- Crafted business models for small scale private businesses

Aerospace Technician, Phoenix, AZ

May 2011 - May 2016

Boeing Aerospace, Overhaul Technician	May 2015 - May 2016
Aeroturbine, Aircraft Repair Technician	Feb 2014 - Nov 2015
Honeywell Aerospace, Flow-line Assembly Technician	Jul 2013 - Feb 2014
Nabtesco Aerospace, Research and Development Technician (Seattle, WA)	Feb 2013 - Jun 2013
Boeing Aerospace, Overhaul Technician	May 2011 - Nov 2012

- Routinely updated management facing metrics for production control.
- Achieved a personal acceptance rate of 100% for all assemblies tested.
- Closely working with electrical and mechanical engineers to develop an automated testing system for critical systems.

Education

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

Nov 2021

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate

Nominated Keynote Speaker for performance during boot camp.

Arizona State University East

FAA Airframe & Powerplant License

Nov 2013

Self educated to gain license through university

United States Army Aviation Logistics School

Apr 2007

Aircraft Powerplant Repairer Certificate

Graduated with honors